marketingresearchresources.com 2011-11-24

# Marketing & Research Resources, Inc. Privacy Policy

Marketing & Research Resources, Inc. ("M&RR") is committed to ensuring the privacy of our survey participants. We take that commitment seriously, and you can be assured that your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal information is our top priority. M&RR complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. M&RR has certified that it adheres to the Safe harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view M&RR's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. Please take some time to review our privacy policy below.

## How we use the information we collect

When you participate in one of our surveys, M&RR uses your responses along with other participants' responses to inform clients about people's attitudes about their products or services. As part of the research process, your responses are analyzed in aggregate with all the other respondents' information, and your individual responses are not linked to your personally identifiable information without your permission. We are interested only in your opinions and will never try to sell you anything.

If we collect your postal address in any survey, it is to mail any survey-related incentives. We never share your e-mail or postal address without your permission.

We use your e-mail address to send you invitations to participate in new Internet surveys and to contact you with messages if you would happen to win a sweepstakes. When you participate in one of our Internet surveys, our servers only record the time you start and finish our survey. We may place "cookies" on your computer when you take our surveys; these "cookies" are used only to ensure survey security and do not collect or extract any personal information from your computer.

In phone surveys, your phone number has been either randomly generated or selected from a list provided by a reputable sample house or by our client. M&RR is not subject to The Do-Not-Call Implementation Act of 2003 or the FCC's National Do Not Call Registry. As a market research firm, we are interested only in your opinions and will never try to sell you anything. Your responses in our phone surveys are never linked to your phone number.

## How we protect your information

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online, by telephone, or by mail.

We may occasionally need to share your information with third parties, our agents or sub-contractors, who perform services on our behalf such as reward fulfillment, web hosting, data analysis, and the like. When we use such agents or sub-contractors, we require these parties to comply with our privacy policy and utilize all appropriate security and confidentiality measures (i.e., a "chain of trust").

## Child Privacy

M&RR abides by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) legislated by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) in 1998. We do not knowingly contact children under the age of 13. If you are a parent whose child has been contacted by M&RR and wish for your child not to have future correspondences, please contact us at [unsubscribe@m-rr.com](mailto:unsubscribe@m-rr.com?subject=Unsubscribe) and we will gladly remove your child's e-mail address and/or phone number from all future e-mail and phone surveys.

## Market Research Ethics

M&RR limits the use of its information for legitimate market research purposes only. M&RR is active in supporting the following organizations created to uphold ethical survey research:

  * Market Research Association (MRA) [[www.mra-net.org](http://www.mra-net.org/)]
  * American Marketing Association (AMA) [[www.marketingpower.com](http://www.marketingpower.com/)]
  * Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO) [[www.casro.org](http://www.casro.org/)]

M&RR is a member of the Better Business Bureau OnLine (BBBOnLine). [[www.bbb.org](http://www.bbb.org/)]

## Your Rights

Should you wish to unsubscribe and stop receiving survey requests, please send a blank e-mail to [unsubscribe@m-rr.com](mailto:unsubscribe@m-rr.com?subject=Unsubscribe) from the e-mail account under which you are subscribed as a survey participant.

If you have additional questions, please contact us at [info@m-rr.com](mailto:info@m-rr.com?subject=Information) anytime. Or write to us at:

Marketing & Research Resources, Inc.  
7101 Guilford Drive, Suite 101  
Frederick, MD 21704  
240-575-7100
